A lawman and his sons face the ultimate test of courage.
Cahill: United States Marshal is a drama, western
film directed by Andrew V. McLaglen.
Cahill is the toughest U.S.
Marshal they've got, just the sound of his name makes bad guys stop in their tracks, so
when his two young boy's want to get his attention they decide to rob a bank.
They end up getting more than they bargained for.
J.D. Cahill, played by John Wayne.
Abe Fraser, played by George Kennedy.
Daniel "Danny" Cahill, played by Gary Grimes.
Lightfoot, played by Neville Brand.
Billy Joe Cahill, played by Clay O'Brien.
Mrs. Hetty Green, played by Marie Windsor.
Cahill U.S.
Marshal is a 1973 American Western film in Technicolor starring
John Wayne as a driven lawman in a black hat.
The film was directed by Andrew V.
McLaglen and filmed on location in Durango, Mexico.
The supporting cast features George Kennedy, Neville Brand, Marie Windsor, Royal Dano,
Denver Pyle, Jackie Coogan, Harry Carey Jr., Paul Fix and Hank Worden.
The film explores themes of prison escape, u.s. marshal, father son conflict.
The tone is emotional.